{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Practical Research 1",
    "Term": "First Quarter",
    "Title": "Module 3 - Lesson 2",
    "LastModified": "14 August 2025",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "Module 3 - Lesson 2.pdf"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "What guideline for choosing a topic suggests you should be interested in it because you have experienced it?",
      "answer": "Interest in the subject matter",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Personal resources",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline is important so that when you decide on a topic, sources of information are accessible?",
      "answer": "Availability of information",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Personal resources",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What must be considered to ensure a research topic is current and significant?",
      "answer": "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
      "choices": [
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Personal resources",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Interest in the subject matter"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline considers if a topic is limited to what the teacher suggests?",
      "answer": "Limitations on the subject",
      "choices": [
        "Availability of information",
        "Timeliness and relevance of the topic",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Personal resources"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What guideline requires you to consider if you can finish the research in terms of your intellectual and financial capabilities?",
      "answer": "Personal resources",
      "choices": [
        "Interest in the subject matter",
        "Personal resources",
        "Limitations on the subject",
        "Availability of information"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of topic should be avoided because it is highly opinionated?",
      "answer": "Controversial topics",
      "choices": [
        "Controversial topics",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Too broad subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What kind of topic should be avoided as it sparks disagreement or debate?",
      "answer": "Controversial topics",
      "choices": [
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics",
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What type of topic requires expertise and should be avoided if you don't have enough knowledge about it?",
      "answer": "Highly technical subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What subjects are made difficult by the unavailability of updated reading materials?",
      "answer": "Hard to investigate subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Controversial topics",
        "Hard to investigate subjects"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the result if you deal with topics that lack focus?",
      "answer": "Too broad subjects",
      "choices": [
        "Too broad subjects",
        "Hard to investigate subjects",
        "Highly technical subjects",
        "Controversial topics"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the remedy if you lack focus because you deal with broad topics?",
      "answer": "narrow it down",
      "choices": [
        "make it controversial",
        "add personal resources",
        "make it technical",
        "narrow it down"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is considered the most important element of your research as it clearly expresses the problem to be explored?",
      "answer": "Research title",
      "choices": [
        "Research title",
        "Subject matter",
        "Respondents",
        "Time period"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the subject matter or topic to be investigated?",
      "answer": "What",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "Who",
        "When",
        "What"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the place or locale where the research is to be conducted?",
      "answer": "Where",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "What",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the participants or respondents of the study?",
      "answer": "Who",
      "choices": [
        "What",
        "Where",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    },
    {
      "question": "In formulating a research title, what contains the time period of the conduct of the study?",
      "answer": "When",
      "choices": [
        "Where",
        "What",
        "Who",
        "When"
      ],
      "reference": "Writing a Research Title",
      "term": "Module 3 Lesson 2"
    }
  ]
}